<data>
	<projects>
		<projectType id="apps" label="Applications">
			<project id="safety-shield" name="Safety Shield" latest="true">
				<client>Intrado</client>
				<scope>FirstNet certified Mobile Application (iOS/Android) &amp; Web Application.</scope>
				<tech>HTML, SASS, Typescript, React, Cordova, Swift, JAVA</tech>
				<desc>A comprehensive safety management platform designed primarily for schools and educational institutions to enhance emergency preparedness and response. My role as lead developer included creating a Website and Mobile application to facilitate.</desc>
				<link>https://intradosafe.com</link>
			</project>
			<project id="liv" name="Laaser911 Incident Viewer" latest="true">
				<client>Laaser911</client>
				<scope>Mobile Friendly Web Application &amp; PWA</scope>
				<tech>HTML, SASS, Typescript, React, Google Maps, Custom React state management.</tech>
				<desc>A 911 safety management application designed for PSAPs (Public Safety Answering Points) to track in real time 911 emergencies and provide location accurate information for first responders.</desc>
				<link>https://laaser911.com/liv</link>
			</project>
			<project id="prizm5" name="Prizm 5">
				<client>Primz5</client>
				<scope>Mobile Application (iOS/Android) &amp; Website</scope>
				<tech>Actionscript 3, Flash, AIR, Starling, Feathers, ANE, XML, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Photoshop, Illustrator</tech>
				<desc>A cross-platform mobile application and website built to showcase the Prizm5 classifications for postal codes throughout Canada. PRIZM5 classifies all Canadians into one of 68 lifestyle types—with names like Cosmopolitan Elite, Boomerang City, Rustic Roads and Lunch at Tim's—based on their demographics, marketplace preferences and psychographic Social Values. Using PRIZM5, businesses and not-for-profits can guide their marketing campaigns and media strategies for reaching Canada's consumer segments.</desc>
				<link>Offline</link>
			</project>
			<project id="pfccc" name="PhoneFusion Call Control">
				<client>PhoneFusion</client>
				<scope>Desktop Application (Windows/Mac), Mobile Application (iOS/Android), Website</scope>
				<tech>Actionscript 3, Flash, AIR, Starling, Feathers, ANE, JSON, XML, HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, Photoshop, Illustrator</tech>
				<desc>A true cross platform application. This application has 1 code base that is shared between 2 applications with 5 end points each. This app enables a user to control their PhoneFusion ONE phone calls.  Answer, transfer, expedite, quick reply, tons of options for controlling calls. Send Faxes, SMS, check voicemail, create video conferences, multi-account support. </desc>
				<link>Internal Enterprise Solution</link>
			</project>
			<project id="sbv" name="SBV">
				<client>SBV Workforce Management</client>
				<scope>Mobile Application (iOS/Android)</scope>
				<tech>Actionscript 3, AIR, Starling, Feathers, ANE, JSON, Photoshop, Illustrator</tech>
				<desc>A cross-platform mobile application built to handle time tracking, scheduling, messaging &amp; clocking in/out for SBV employees.</desc>
				<link>Internal Enterprise Solution</link>
			</project>
			<project id="act" name="Act Call Control">
				<client>Act!</client>
				<scope>Mobile Application (iOS/Android)</scope>
				<tech>Actionscript 3, AIR, Starling, Feathers, ANE, JSON, XML, Photoshop, Illustrator</tech>
				<desc>A cross-platform mobile application built for Act to Answer, transfer, expedite, quick reply, and many more options for controlling calls. Send Faxes, SMS, check voicemail, multi-account support. </desc>
				<link>Internal Enterprise Solution</link>
			</project>
			<project id="smsstats" name="SMS Stats">
				<client>PhoneFusion</client>
				<scope>Desktop Application (Windows/Mac), Mobile Application (iOS/Android), Website</scope>
				<tech>Actionscript 3, Flash, AIR, XML, HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, Photoshop, Illustrator</tech>
				<desc>A statistical display application created to showcase the accuracy of SMS messages of various platforms. </desc>
				<link>Offline</link>
			</project>
		</projectType>
		<projectType id="games" label="Games">
			<project id="syp" name="See You Poker">
				<client>See You Poker</client>
				<scope>Desktop Application (Windows/Mac), Mobile Application (iOS/Android)</scope>
				<tech>Red5 Streaming Video, Actionscript 3, Flash, AIR, Starling, Feathers, ANE, JSON, XML, HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, Photoshop, Illustrator. SSO with Facebook.</tech>
				<desc>A cross-platform moblie/desktop/website game that allows users to play video streaming Texas Holdem Poker.</desc>
				<link>Offline</link>
			</project>
			<project id="can-u-sing" name="Can U Sing">
				<client>Can U Sing</client>
				<scope>Desktop Application (Windows/Mac), Mobile Application (iOS/Android)</scope>
				<tech>Actionscript 3, Flash, AIR, Starling, Feathers, ANE, JSON, XML, HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, Photoshop, Illustrator. SSO with Twitter, Facebook, Instagram.</tech>
				<desc>A mobile application built to the ask the question "Can You Sing?". The mobile application implements various FFT algorithms to analyze a user's voice to match their tone against lots of popular/modern songs.</desc>
				<link>Offline</link>
			</project>
			<project id="frenchie-quest" name="Frenchie Quest">
				<client>Myself</client>
				<scope>Desktop Application (Windows/Mac), Mobile Application (iOS/Android)</scope>
				<tech>Actionscript 3, AIR, Starling, Feathers, ANE, JSON, Photoshop, Illustrator</tech>
				<desc>Yes that's right, I made a cross-platform (mobile/desktop) game featuring my own dogs Ganon &amp; Loki. This was created simply because I wanted the challenge of building a side-scrolling game and what better topic than using your own dogs!</desc>
				<link>https://frenchiegames.itch.io/frenchie-quest</link>
			</project>
			<project id="hf3" name="Coca-Cola Happiness Factory">
				<client>Coca-Cola</client>
				<scope>Website / Games</scope>
				<tech>Actionscript 3, HTML, CSS, Javascript, JSON, Photoshop, Illustrator</tech>
				<desc>One of the lead developer's for Coca-Cola's Happiness Factory 3. My tasks included creating the overall website, 2 of the 5 games, the 'Theater' section, and making sure everything translated to over 70+ languages (without reloading).</desc>
				<link>https://thefwa.com/cases/happiness-factory-3</link>
			</project>
		</projectType>
		<projectType id="web" label="Websites">
			<project id="laaser911" name="Laaser911" latest="true">
				<client>Laaser911</client>
				<scope>Mobile Friendly Website</scope>
				<tech>HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Wordpress, Photoshop, Illustrator</tech>
				<desc>I developed the website for Laaser 911, a critical service provider specializing in emergency response solutions. The primary goal of this project was to create a fast loading and user-friendly website to help explain the services that Laaser911 offers. My responsibilities included designing a responsive interface and implementing wordpress to allow easily updating any section of the website.</desc>
				<link>https://www.laaser911.com</link>
			</project>
			<project id="phone-fusion" name="Phone Fusion">
				<client>PhoneFusion</client>
				<scope>Mobile Friendly Website</scope>
				<tech>HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Wordpress, Photoshop, Illustrator</tech>
				<desc>I developed the website for PhoneFusion, a comprehensive telecommunications service provider, to offer users a seamless platform for exploring and managing services such as voicemail, call forwarding, and messaging. My responsibilities included designing a responsive user interface, integrating front-end and back-end services via RESTful APIs, and implementing secure user authentication. I focused on optimizing performance for quick load times and conducted extensive testing to ensure cross-browser compatibility.</desc>
				<link>https://www.phonefusion.com</link>
			</project>
			<project id="vendorply" name="Vendorply">
				<client>Vendorply</client>
				<scope>Mobile Friendly Website</scope>
				<tech>HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, TweenMax, Photoshop, Illustrator</tech>
				<desc>Something should go here.</desc>
				<link>https://www.vendorply.com</link>
			</project>
			<project id="bjc" name="Boca Jewish Center">
				<client>Boca Jewish Center</client>
				<scope>Mobile Friendly Website</scope>
				<tech>HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, TweenMax, Shulcloud, Photoshop, Illustrator</tech>
				<desc>Something should go here.</desc>
				<link>Offline</link>
			</project>
		</projectType>
		<projectType id="other" label="Other">
			<project id="sauron-holocron" name="Sauron Holocron">
				<client>Myself</client>
				<scope>A Sith Holocron for The Dark Lord Sauron!</scope>
				<tech>3D printing, Arduino to control sound and LED lights.</tech>
				<desc>A fun mashup of The Lord of the Rings and Star Wars to create a original item.  A fun 3d printing project that combines 3d printing with Arduino/Sound/LED Lights/Rechargable USB batter and has 8 animation modes and can play various audio clips from The Lord of the Rings / The Hobbit.</desc>
				<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eRCXtB5M6yg</link>
			</project>
			<project id="iron-man-helmet" name="Iron Man Helmet">
				<client>Myself</client>
				<scope>A functional replica of Iron Man's helmet design to fit my own head.</scope>
				<tech>3D printing, Arduino to control sound, servo motors, LED lights. Uses RF or Smart Home implementation to control the helmet.</tech>
				<desc>A fun project for myself where I scaled and 3d printed an Iron Man helmet to fit my head. It's complete with Sound, LED lights for the eyes and uses servo motors to open/close the faceplate. It can be controlled via buttons or a RF module for handfree control via Smart Home implementation. </desc>
				<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7ywNrnEcuzg</link>
			</project>
			<project id="gimli-axes" name="Gimli Axes">
				<client>Myself</client>
				<scope>Creating accurate to scale replica's of Gimli's Axes from the Lord of the Rings.</scope>
				<tech>3D printing</tech>
				<desc>As a collector of LOTR replicas I took it upon myself to create some replica's that couldn't be found anywhere else online.</desc>
				<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mYc2RGRxpzQ</link>
			</project>
		</projectType>
	</projects>
</data>